Contact

Rhonda Taff, South Wales, Wales +447477115523 (Mobile) alexak@hotmail.co.uk

www.linkedin.com/in/ alexanderoluwaseunkwesi (LinkedIn) www.uvclegal.uk (Company)

Top Skills

JavaScript HTML5 CSS3

Languages

Spanish (Elementary)
French (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Elementary)

Certifications

Certified Internet Of Things Expert
Certified PHP Expert
Certified Python Expert

Honors-Awards

Neatness Award
Athletics Gold Winner

Alexander Kwesi

Tech is key to providing high performing solutions | Web Developer Cardiff, Wales, United Kingdom

Summary

I have 6 years and 7 months of experience working within the Computing and Information Technology industry, throughout my time, I have been placed in different roles, where some required me to take up different job types at the same time, in order to relieve staff from the stress faced with working in a fast-paced environment. During my time with the sister company of NIMASA, I was the first developer by choice, over the course of my time spent there I was nominated for an award for the high-performance solutions I provided, but because of minor inaccuracies in the development of a Forum Web Application to replace their bulletin styled way of distributing paper-based information, I wasn't awarded, but I would have saved the company 10% on the total expenditure on buying paper.

Experience

University of South Wales 10 months

Course Representative February 2023 - Present (10 months) Pontypridd, Rhondda Cynon Taff

Course Reps share the views of their fellow students with their Course Team so that learning and teaching can be improved for current and future students and ensure issues are brought to the course team's attention. This is important as it gives the student voice a central role in shaping students' own learning experience. Course Reps also work with Student Voice Reps if an academic issue affects students across their Faculty. You can find more information about the role of Course Reps on the Students' Union website.

Career Ambassador March 2023 - Present (9 months) Pontypridd, Rhondda Cynon Taff

A career ambassador is someone who helps high school, college and entrylevel job seekers with their career search. They might work with a career

Page 1 of 5

services team to promote specific opportunities, help students and others searching for a new position connect with worthwhile positions and counsel others in their job search process. Most often, career ambassadors work for college career services departments and are often students themselves, completing work-study programs for their schools. Career ambassadors can use their training and skills to promote unique career options and review new professionals' application materials.

Yeesh Company Link Builder July 2023 - Present (5 months)

Greater Cardiff Area

This is a link to a classical styled website of my resume hosted on google it was created using Hyper Text Mark Up Language and uploaded onto the

Google Cloud Platform where a single index html file was placed in a bucket, the index file uses a platform program file as the format styling of the LinkedIn section, then an iframe element and/or tag was used to render my Curriculum

Vitae to the browser page.

UK Visa Centre

2 years 8 months

Web Developer

April 2021 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Derby, England, United Kingdom

Responsible for designing and developing the company website ensuring it is responsive using

Wix

Communicated with Chief Executive Officer regarding the prerequisite of the website

Managed all phases of design and development including content writing Created the website by interacting with the Wix online editor, dashboard, and other online

resources

Web Content Writer

April 2021 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Derby, England, United Kingdom

Structuring the contents needed by each page, according to section requirements.

Downloading pictures to be used on the website.

Bune Bear PHP Web Developer October 2019 - January 2020 (4 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

I was involved in a mentorship program remotely, I had to maintain an excellent relationship between myself and my mentor, as a result i had to be gracious and thoughtful towards my mentor and expect the same in return, I seek guidiance on what to do from the mentor conveying respect for what the both of us are trying to accomplish.

Some basic premises of what makes me the ideal mentee are:

- 1. Eagerness to learn, admission
- 2. Ability and willingness to work as a team player
- 3. Patience
- 4. Be a risk taker
- 5. Have a positive attitude

Achievements

- Focused efforts on achieving certain goals
- Communicated and used various tools to help make mentor and mentee interact
- Used experience to show motivation and was encouraged and applauded for showing intelligence in completing assigned task
- Slashed development times by 30% researching and adopting different new software programs and becoming familiar with it
- Managed efficient code writing, ensuring they comply with programming standards using a variety of programming languages, including PHP/MySQL, among others
- Managed and built web pages and web application across multiple products
- Maintaining, enhancing and expanding websites as needed through interacting with mentor to achieve a singular goal

Snug Tissue
Full Stack Developer (Freelance Volunteer)
April 2017 - July 2017 (4 months)
Warrington, England, United Kingdom

Managed the planning, designing, development, and testing of the website Employed different web stacks in developing the e-commerce website Independently wrote the code for verifying bank card payments Nultan Software Engineer March 2016 - August 2016 (6 months)

Lagos, Lagos State, Nigeria

Saas Maintenance using the MVC framework, changing menu orders, structuring dashboard options, writing code using collections and scripts, assisting in deployment onto a server, placing in the end user's onsite premises, working Saturdays on occasion, and having meetings on occasion.

Nigerian Shippers Council Web Developer June 2011 - June 2012 (1 year 1 month) Lagos, Nigeria

Used Project Management Techniques to identify the key stakeholders, ensuring they are kept happy, and detail all tasks accordingly, selecting the most appropriate technology to adopt as the Project Manager.

Used the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) which is also the Web Development Lifecycle to Implement a website.

Used Communication to interact with stakeholders.

BizDataUSA

Web Developer October 2008 - August 2009 (11 months)

Lagos, Nigeria

Building websites using technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

This includes the layout of websites, as well as frameworks used to deliver the

content that will be displayed on the site.

Modifying and updating websites according to a company or client's specifications.

Ensuring that websites are visually attractive and user-friendly.

Collaborating with other colleagues, such as content creators, copywriters, graphic designers, marketing managers, and IT staff.

Testing websites and troubleshooting any problems as soon as they are identified

This job also requires me to do the following work:

- Know HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and other relevant web design coding languages

- Create and test applications for websites
- Collaborate
- Present design specs
- Work with graphics and other designers
- Troubleshoot website problems
- Maintain and update websites
- -Monitor website traffic
- Stay up-to-date on technology

Achievements

- Writing code in one or more programming or scripting languages, such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in Dreamweaver
- Synchronised website with CEO's version
- Designed and hand coded new websites
- Liaised with clients and CEO to achieve deliverables

Education

University of South Wales

Master's degree, Computing and Information Systems

New Horizon

Information Technology · (October 2016 - February 2017)

University of Wolverhampton

Bachelor's degree, Computer Studies · (September 2006 - July 2008)

Dudley College of Technology

HND - Computing, Information Technology (September 2002 - May 2005)

APTECH Computer Education

Information Technology · (January 2001 - June 2002)